christiebrinkleyskincare.com 2017-05-05

# Privacy Policy | Christie Brinkley Skincare

We provide products and services through our websites, mobile websites, mobile applications, emails, offline or by other interactions and communications ("Services"). These highlights are to help you understand how we collect, use and disclose user information to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or continue using the Services. Please also read our full Privacy Policy for details and defined terms. 

When you use our Services or make a purchase, you voluntarily share certain personal information with us such as your name, e-mail address, address, mobile number, and/or credit or debit card or bank account information and with your prior permission connect through social media networks such as Facebook.More Info 

We use tracking technologies such as cookies and other similar technologies to measure usage and your online viewing and to provide information that will be of most interest to you. We may collect additional information from you if you access our Services through a mobile device, including a unique device identifier and specific location information if you have elected to share that information on your device More Info 

You agree that we can retain the information for as long as you have an account or for legitimate business purposes as outlined in this Privacy Policy. We may also retain certain information for archival purposes and if required by law. More Info 

By using our Services you agree that we may share your personal information and other information we collect with our marketing partners, affiliated companies, our service providers, mobile carriers, social networks, legal and law enforcement, and others if there is a change of control.More Info 

You can change your information by contacting customer service at info@brinkleysupport.com or calling 1-800-548-1736. You can control how and when you want to receive promotional notifications from us. More Info 

You agree that we may notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a new "Effective Date" on the Privacy Policy. More Info 

Questions about our Privacy Policy or about our handling of your information may be sent to privacy@BrinkleySupport.com or as otherwise set forth in the Privacy Policy More Info 

Effective Date: December 7, 2016

Christie Brinkley Skincare, LLC ("CB, "we" "us", "our") has developed this Privacy Policy which details important information regarding the use and disclosure of user information collected on CB owned websites, mobile websites, mobile applications, emails, offline or other interactions and communications with CB, and related services (each and collectively referred to as "Services") that link to or reference this Privacy Policy . CB provides this Privacy Policy to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or continue to use the Services and the choices we offer for you to manage the information we collect related to the use of the Services. Each time that you access or use Services, you are agreeing to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy or Terms of Service which govern your use of our Services, please discontinue accessing or using the Services.

**1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

You can browse our Services without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information including but not limited to your name, email address, phone number, mobile telephone number, debit or credit card information or physical contact information about yourself. If you create an account or purchase any of our products or Services, you choose to give us your personal information and are not anonymous to us. When you create an account or use certain of our Services or otherwise engage with our Services, you may provide certain additional information such as username. You may also provide payment information such as credit or debit card information, name and billing address. 

You may give us your personal information so we can send you communications you request. Details of how you can opt-out of receiving any promotional communications from us are detailed in the section headed Choice and Opt-out.

When using our Services or third party social networking services (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Google +) (each and collectively, a "Social Network"), you will have the option to connect your activity on our Services with your Social Network information and activity. If you permit a connection between a Social Network and our Services we (and that Social Network) may be able to identify you and to associate information received from the connection with information we already have about you. Please review the Social Network’s privacy policy and choices for sharing information of any Social Network connected to our Services. 

From time-to-time we may request information from you and other users via surveys, contests, sweepstakes or other promotions. Participation in these surveys, contests, sweepstakes or other promotions is completely voluntary. Contact information may be used as set forth in this Privacy Policy and as set forth in the applicable official rules, to notify the winners and award prizes and file winners’ information as required by law. Survey information will be used for the purposes of the survey. 

Any information or content you post when participating with the Services, Social Networks, plug ins or other applications becomes public information, depending upon your privacy settings, and is subject to redistribution by CB and other third parties. There is no expectation of privacy when posting content or otherwise participating in interactive forums and we have no control over how those users may use the information you make public. Therefore, you should exercise caution and discretion when deciding to disclose your personal information in a submission or posting. 

We may collect additional information from you if you access Services through a mobile device, for example your unique device identifier, device operating system, mobile carrier, location or GPS/geo-location, and billing information which we may collect when you opt in for us to do so. When you use our Services we may request your permission to collect your location information. Please be advised some features will not be available if you choose not to provide your location data to us. However the degree to which your location can be identified depends on the device you are using (e.g. laptop, smartphone, tablet) and how you are connected to the internet (e.g. via cable broadband connection, Wi-Fi, etc.). If you enable location services for our Services we may collect location data periodically as you use or leave open our Services. We may also use this data internally or in conjunction with our third party service providers to customize your experience and provide offers that may be relevant to you. Depending on the platform you use to access our Services (e.g., Apple, iOS, Google, Android, Windows, etc.) you may be able to control from within the settings on your wireless device or the Service(s) whether location data is collected. 

From time to time you may choose to submit personal information about other people to invite them to share content on or use our Services. Inviting friends is always optional. Please be aware that when you use any send-to-a-friend functionality on the Services, your e-mail address may be included in the communication sent to your friend. 

The information we collect may be combined with information from outside records (e.g., demographic information, navigation information, additional contact information) that we have acquired in accordance with the law. We use this information to help us maintain the accuracy of the information we collect, to customize our communications so that we can inform you of products, services and offers that might be of interest and for internal business analysis or other business purposes. 

**2\. INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**.

Our goal is to collect and use only that information that we think is required for our legitimate business interests, in order to better understand your interests and improve your experience of using the Services. 

In addition to any personal information or other information that you choose to submit to us, we and our business partners may use a variety of tracking technologies that automatically (or passively) collect certain information described in this Privacy Policy from your computer, mobile, or other access device whenever you visit or interact with the Services ("Usage Information"). We use tracking technologies (including cookies, flash cookies, web beacons/GIFs, embedded scripts, e-tags/cache browsers/web logs) to collect Usage Information. We may use tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, including: _Operationally Necessary_. We may use tracking technologies required for system administration, to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping cart functionality. We may also collect user names and password information from you when you log in, as well as computer and/or connection information. _Performance-Related._ We may use cookies or other tracking technologies to assess the performance of our Services, including as part of our analytic practices to improve the content offered through the Services. _Functionality-Related._ We may use tracking technologies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited the Services before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify the features in which you may have the greatest interest. Keep in mind that certain features of our Services are available only through the use of tracking technologies. 

You may encounter tracking technologies/cookies from our third party service providers that we have allowed on our Services that assist us with various aspects of our operations and Services to provide us with information about your interests from your web viewing on other sites or applications. You may find out more information about these third parties and their practices and your choices on how such data is collected by clicking here. Our Services may contain links to third party websites, applications or products. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties and we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website that collects personally information from you. 

**3\. HOW WE USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION**

When using our Services or when using certain Social Networks, you may have the option to connect your activity on our Services with your Social Network activity. If you authorize such a connection, you permit us to share or publish information about your activity on our Services, with that Social Network and its users. Information we may share with a Social Network may include, but is not limited to: technical information about your Services activity, your Services comments or any videos you watch on our Services. If you permit a connection between a Social Network and our Services, we (and that Social Network) may be able to identify you and to associate information received pursuant to the connection with information we already have about you. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policy and privacy control options of any Social Network with which you choose to share information or connect to our Services. 

Certain areas on our Services may be provided to you in association with third parties ("Co-Branded Areas"). Such Co-Branded Areas will identify the third party. If you elect to interact with the products and/or services provided at these Co-Branded Areas, you either will be providing your personal information to both us and the third party or we might be providing your personal information directly to the third party in order for that third party to fulfill their products and services directly with you. Your personal information will be subject to this Privacy Policy as well as the privacy policy and practices of such third party. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those third parties and we suggest you review the respective privacy policies of those third parties to learn more about their privacy practices. 

We may use Information that we collect about you: (1) to respond to your requests (2) to provide customer service (e.g., to fulfill product orders made by you, to resolve disputes, problems with your account or our Services, administer a contest, sweepstakes or promotion, or to provide information to third parties at your request (3) to improve our Services and to customize your experience; (4) to give you information about your account or our Services; (5) for internal business purposes; and (6) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

We use aggregate information about our users and non-personal information to analyze the Services and user behavior and prepare aggregated reports which we share with third parties. 

We use your information to contact you to maintain your account, to comply with your stated communication preferences and to provide other Services requested by you, as described at the time when we collect the information from you, or to contact you for other purposes authorized by law. 

When you access the Services on a mobile device, we may use the information collected for any purpose set forth in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as locally based search results, and other personalized content. 

We may also use your email address or mobile phone number to send you updates and communications about our products and services or other messages, such as newsletters, text messages, changes to features of the Services, or special offers. You will be given the opportunity, in any promotional email or text message that we send to you to opt out of receiving such messages in the future. To see your choice and opt-out options, click here.

We may, without your consent, access and disclose your information, any communications sent or received by you, and any other information that we may have about you or your account as may be permitted or required by law (including, but not limited to, court order or subpoena), or to prevent or investigate suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, which we encourage you to read in conjunction with this Privacy Policy, or activity that appears to us to be illegal or may expose us to legal liability. Additionally, we may disclose your information in situations that we believe may involve potential threats to the physical safety of any person or property if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat. 

If CB or any of its brands or divisions is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, personal information of our users may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction. Information about our users may also need to be disclosed in connection with a commercial transaction where we or any one of our businesses are seeking financing, investment, support or funding. 

Personally identifiable information that you provide to us in the course of requesting a product or service through the Services may be gathered and stored in one or more of our corporate databases. We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is permitted or required by law. 

**4\. ACCESSING AND CHANGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

. Account holders can review and change personal information at any time by accessing their accounts on the Services. If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information you provided to us is not correct and you cannot change it by accessing your account contact us_info@brinkleysupport.com. You should promptly update your account information if it changes or becomes inaccurate. 

If you have an account you may close that account at any time. Please email info@brinkleysupport.com or call 1-800-548-1736 for information on how to close your account. We may retain some information from closed accounts so that we can comply with law, prevent fraud, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our Terms of Service, or take other actions permitted by law. Likewise if your account is terminated or suspended, we may maintain some information to prevent re-registration. 

If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information you provided to us is not correct contact us at [info@brinkleysupport.com](mailto:info@brinkleysupport.com) or call 1-800-548-1736. You should promptly update your personal information if it changes or becomes inaccurate. 

**5\. CHOICE AND OPT OUT**

You may choose not to receive our promotional communications or you may opt out of our sharing information with third parties for marketing purposes by visiting [here](https://www.acmg-unsu8scr13e.com/unsub/unsub.form?id=2b701b7ef252464e7f40d577a18119d17e4b7796e123beb4c9a2a952aa26507d). You may also click the unsubscribe link in the footer of any e-mail or newsletter. You may also e-mail us at info@brinkleysupport.com. It may take up to 10 days for us to process an opt-out request. Just follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each email or click "STOP" on a mobile text. You may also contact our privacy administrator at privacy@BrinkleySupport.com. You may also send mail making any such requests to the following address:  
Christie Brinkley Skincare, LLC.  
P.O. Box 1366  
Hoboken  
NJ 07030.

Information that you disclose while participating in the Services may be public and subject to redistribution by us and any third-party that reviews your Social Network profile or information that you post. Please be aware that CB is not responsible for the uses or copies of your public postings on or through Services which are downloaded by third parties. To change your privacy settings please contact us. 

You may not opt-out of administrative e-mails (for example e-mails about your transactions or policy changes) for your registered account. 

You may request that we deactivate or delete your account by contacting us. You may also e-mail us at info@brinkleysupport.com. When you deactivate your account or ask that we delete your content on a Service we will retain logs and information about you along with an archival copy of your information, which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Service but which might be used by us for recordkeeping and internal purposes, including enforcing our Terms of Service and demographic, reporting and research purposes. 

We will endeavor to comply with your requests as soon as reasonably possible but please note that changes requested of us may not be effective immediately. Unless required by law, we are not responsible for informing third parties with whom we have already shared your information of any changes requested pursuant to this section, or for removing information from or causing information to be removed from the databases or records of such entities. 

**6\. IMPORTANT DISCLOSURES**

When you provide us with information in connection with a particular activity or otherwise sign up for our Services or provide your contact information, including an email address or telephone number in connection with that activity, product or Service, you agree that this action constitutes a purchase or inquiry establishing a business relationship with us. You expressly consent to our communicating with you future information about our Services using the information you provided to us. You also attest that you have the legal authority over any telephone number you provide to us and can provide us with the authorization to contact you. This means we may contact you, in person or by recorded message, by e-mail, telephone and/or mobile telephone number (including use of automated dialing equipment), text (SMS) message, or any other means of communication that your wireless or other telecommunications device may be capable of receiving, in accordance with law. 

To the extent hyperlinks may be utilized to access external or third party sites or applications, you should be aware that these external or third party sites are not controlled by us and, therefore, are not subject to this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you check the privacy policies of those third party sites or applications to determine how your personal information will be utilized by the proprietors. 

We implement security measures to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control, including to protect your data. SSL is encryption technology that helps safeguard your personally identifiable information against misuse by unauthorized individuals. However, despite our efforts, no system can completely guaranty that there will never be unauthorized access to your personal information, and your use of the Services indicates that you are willing to assume this risk. 

We do not represent or warrant that any of our Services is appropriate or available for use in any particular jurisdiction. Those who choose to access the Services do so on their own initiative and at their own risk, and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations. We may limit access to our Services, in whole or in part, to any person, geographic area or jurisdiction we choose, at any time and in our sole discretion. By using our Services and submitting any personal information, you consent to the transfer of personal information to other countries, such as the United States, which may provide a level of data security different from your country of residence. You are also consenting to the application of United States law in all matters concerning the Services. 

The Services are directed to a general audience and we restrict the use of our Services to individuals age 13 and above. We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under 13 years of age and if we obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user’s personal information from our systems. If you become aware that anyone under 13 has provided us with personal information, please contact us in accordance with the "Contacting Us" in Section 7 below 

This Privacy Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to users of the Services. 

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. You agree that we may notify you about material changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a notice on the Services. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Services, with the "Effective Date" posted at the top of the Policy. You should check the Services frequently for updates. By accessing the Services after the Effective Date you are deemed to consent to our then-current Privacy Policy. 

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests may be made only once a year and are free of charge. To make such a request, please contact us. For all requests, you must put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. You need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, mail, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information. 

**7\. CONTACTING US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the practices of CB, please contact us at 1-800-548-1736 or write to us at:  
Christie Brinkley Skincare, LLC.  
P.O. Box 1366  
Hoboken  
NJ 07030.

**Copyright © 2017, Christie Brinkley Skincare, LLC. All rights reserved.**

 **THIRD PARTIES PROVIDERS OF ANALYTICS TOOLS**

This is a list of third parties we have hired to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage and browsing patters of users of the Services.

Google [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
To provide web site visitors more choice on how their data is collected by Google Analytics, Google has developed an Opt-out Browser add-on, which is available by visiting Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/> to enable you to opt-out of Google’s programs.  

Flurry [http://www.flurry.com/about-us/legal/privacy.html](https://www.flurry.com/about-us/legal/privacy.html)

hasOffers [http://mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/](https://mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/)

MixPanel <https://mixpanel.com/privacy/>

Crashlytics [http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/](https://try.crashlytics.com/terms/)

Crittercism <https://www.crittercism.com/privacy-policy/>

In particular, we use Google AdWords Remarketing to advertise Christie Brinkley Skincare across the Internet, in particular on the Google Display Network.

• AdWords remarketing will display ads to you based on what parts of the Christie Brinkley Skincare website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your web browser.

• This cookie does not in any way identify you or give access to your computer or mobile device.

• The cookie is used to indicate to other websites that “This person visited a particular page, so show them ads relating to that page.”

• Google AdWords Remarketing allows us to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and only display ads that are relevant to you.

• If you do not wish to see ads from Christie Brinkley Skincare you can opt out in several ways:

**EXAMPLES OF TRACKING TOOLS**

**Cookies**. A cookie is a data file placed on a device when it is used to visit the Services.  We use cookies to collect information for record keeping purposes, to make it easier to navigate the Services.  Cookies are stored on users' hard drives.  We use both "session ID cookies"; and "persistent cookies.";  Session ID cookies are used to store information while a user is logged into the Services and expire when the user closes his/her browser.  Persistent cookies are used to make tasks like logging into the Services easier for returning users by remembering a user's login information.  Persistent cookies stay on a user's hard drive from one session to the next.  Flash cookies, known as local shared objects, are data files placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device to personalize your visit.  Our third-party service providers also may use Flash cookies to collect and store information.  Flash cookies are different from standard browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages.  You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a persistent or session cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off such cookies through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.  However, cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, please clickwww.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html.  If you choose to disable cookies on your Device, some features of the Services may not function properly.

**Web Beacons/GIFS**. Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as "1×1 GIFs"; or "clear GIFs";) may be included in our web pages and messages.  Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon.  Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to our Services, to monitor how users navigate the Services, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

**Embedded Scripts**. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Services, such as the links you click on.  The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device used to access Services from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Services, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**HTML5**. We use HTML5 in some of our applications, including in our mobile website for the iPhone or iPad.  HTML5 has browser web storage that does not rely on traditional browser cookies.  Like Flash cookies, HTML5 cookies are not stored in a browser "cookies"; file and, like Flash cookies, can be used to track users across websites.  To our knowledge there is currently no known way for a user of a mobile device to remove HTML5 tracking and storage.

**e-tags/cache browers/web logs**. Like most standard website servers, we log IP addresses (a unique number assigned to every computer on the Internet) and device identification in order to improve security, analyze trends and administer the Services.  We may track your movement within the Services, the pages from which you were referred, access times and browser types.  This information may include the browser you are using, the Internet address from which you linked to our Services, the operating system of your computer, the unique IP address of the computer or device identification from the mobile device that you used to access our Services and usage and browsing habits.  We use this information in the aggregate to gauge the effectiveness, usage, and popularity of our Services, track information for statistical purposes, help diagnose and troubleshoot server malfunctions, analyze trends, track user movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information.  We may also use individual information we collect through web logs to send you targeted offers and other communications.
